pandawhale.com 2016-11-26

# Privacy Policy - PandaWhale

## PandaWhale Privacy Policy

PandaWhale, Inc. (“PandaWhale”) takes the private nature of your personal information very seriously. This Privacy Policy (which we adapted from a policy originally provided by Automattic (WordPress.com)) describes how we treat the information we collect when you visit and use the websites and applications provided by PandaWhale and is made available under the Creative Commons Sharealike license. Please read this notice very carefully.

PandaWhale operates several websites including PandaWhale.com and 106Miles.net. It is PandaWhale’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, PandaWhale collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. PandaWhale’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how PandaWhale’s visitors use its website. From time to time, PandaWhale may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

PandaWhale also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments. PandaWhale only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to PandaWhale’s websites choose to interact with PandaWhale in ways that require PandaWhale to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that PandaWhale gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account to provide a username and email address or to login through an OAuth provider like Facebook or Twitter. Those who engage in transactions with PandaWhale – by purchasing products or services for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, PandaWhale collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with PandaWhale. PandaWhale does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

PandaWhale may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, PandaWhale may monitor the most popular conversations and comments. PandaWhale may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, PandaWhale does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

PandaWhale discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on PandaWhale’s behalf or to provide services available at PandaWhale’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using PandaWhale’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. PandaWhale will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, PandaWhale discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when PandaWhale believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of PandaWhale, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a PandaWhale website and have supplied your email address, PandaWhale may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with PandaWhale and our products. We primarily use our website to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. PandaWhale takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. PandaWhale uses cookies to help PandaWhale identify and track visitors, their usage of PandaWhale website, and their website access preferences. PandaWhale visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using PandaWhale’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of PandaWhale’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Business Transfers

If PandaWhale, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that PandaWhale goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of PandaWhale may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Advertising

Advertising appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by PandaWhale and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Links to Other Web Sites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the Service, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website's own rules and policies.

### Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. PandaWhale does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register with the service. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information. If you believe that a child has provided PandaWhale with personally identifiable information without the consent of his or her parent or guardian, please contact us at privacy@pandawhale.org.

### You Have Control Over Your Information

You may, of course, decline to submit personally identifiable information through the Service, in which case PandaWhale may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may also update or correct your conversations, comments, account information and email preferences at any time by logging in to your account.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, PandaWhale may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in PandaWhale’s sole discretion. PandaWhale encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a PandaWhale account, you should also check your dashboard for alerts to these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
